Guide to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Subject Files ALBA.VF.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Subject Files
1930-2023, ongoing
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Czech Liberty Fighters Association Archives
Tamiment Library
ALBA.VF.001
12.85 Linear Feet in 5 record cartons, 14 manuscript boxes, 4 oversized flat boxes, 1 flat box, 1 flat file, and 1 shared manuscript box
5 websites in 5 archived websites.
56.8 Megabytes in 44 computer files
The Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) Subject Files (1930-ongoing) are a rich source for background information on the people, events and topics related to the ALBA collections in the Tamiment Library and include coverage of the International Brigades as well. The files contain a variety of documents such as newspaper clippings, flyers, brochures, biographical material, anniversary and exhibit programs, obituaries, and other items. Consult the folder list in this collection to find material on specific events or topics. See the ALBA Vertical File on Individuals to find biographical material on specific individuals.
Scope and Content Note
The Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) Subject Files (1930-ongoing) consists of files of printed ephemera such as broadsides, brochures, bulletins, catalogs, clippings, flyers, leaflets, manifestoes, pamphlets, press releases, reports, reprints and other documents relating to a broad range of subjects connected with the Abraham Lincoln Brigade.
Provenance
The provenance of the materials is varied. Items were obtained through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, arrangements with organizations and bookstores, exchanges with other libraries, and through ongoing collecting by Tamiment staff.
http://www.alba-valb.org/ and http://albavolunteer.org/ were initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2008 and 2010, respectively, as part of the Other Left Activism Web Archive. In November 2015, this website was migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2017, http://resources.alba-valb.org/ was added. In 2021, https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC_eG6lzX4KJPYIHDZCb-LFw/videos/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2022.024. In 2023, https://www.youtube.com/@abrahamlincolnbrigadearchi4395/videos/ was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2023.086.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- African Americans; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- International brigades.; Pamphlets.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, British; Printed ephemera.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Prisoners and prisons.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, Irish.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Veterans.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Refugees.; Spain - History - Civil War, 1936-1939 - Participation, Czech; Clippings (information artifacts); Fliers (printed matter); Brochures.; Press releases.; Bulletins.; Programs (documents); Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, Jewish.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Articles.; Reports.; Broadsides (notices); Czech Liberty Fighters Association Archives; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Abraham Lincoln Battalion; Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives
- Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) (I) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) (II) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- ALBA News: Newsletter, Brandeis University (Box 1, Folder 3)
- ALBA Report: Newsletter, Brandeis University (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Elizabeth Compa Essay (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Abraham Lincoln Brigade: General (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Abraham Lincoln Brigade: New Masses Articles (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Photographs, General, 1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 8, Box Shared Tamiment 189, Folder 15)
- Activists Forever! Friends and Family of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (Box 1, Folder 9)
- African-American Volunteers (Box 1, Folder 10)
- African-American Volunteers: "The Good Fight" (Christopher T. Brooks) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Aid to the Republic: U.S. Organizations (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Aide Enfantine d'Arriere-Garde (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 1)
- Albacete (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Albanian Volunteers (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Ambulance Drivers (Box 1, Folder 15)
- American Committee for a Free Spanish Republic (Box 1, Folder 16)
- American Committee for Spanish Freedom (Box 1, Folder 17)
- American Friends of Spanish Democracy (Box 1, Folder 18)
- American League against War and Fascism (Box 1, Folder 19)
- American Relief Ship for Spain (Box 1, Folder 20)
- American Rescue Ship Mission (Box 1, Folder 21)
- American Society for Technical Aid to Spanish Democracy (Box 1, Folder 22)
- American Student Union (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Amicale des anciens interas du Camp du Vernet d'Ariege (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Amicale des Anciens Volontaires Francais en Espagne Republicaine et des Amis du Peuple Espagnol (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Anarchist Exiles in France (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Anarchists: General (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Anarchists (US) (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Anniversary, 10th (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Anniversary, 14th (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Anniversary, 15th (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Anniversary, 20th (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Anniversary, 21st (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Anniversary, 22nd (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Anniversary, 25th (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Anniversary, 25th (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 2)
- Anniversary, 30th (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Anniversary, 32nd (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Anniversary, 34th (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Anniversary, 35th (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Anniversary, 36th (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Anniversary, 37th (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Anniversary, 39th (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Anniversary, 40th, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 43, Box Shared Tamiment 189, Folder 14)
- Anniversary, 41st (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Anniversary, 42nd (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Anniversary, 43rd (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Anniversary, 44th (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Anniversary, 45th (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Anniversary, 46th (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Anniversary, 47th (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Anniversary, 48th (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Anniversary, 50th (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Anniversary, 50th Booklet (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Anniversary, 51st (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Anniversary, 52nd (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Anniversary, 53rd (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Anniversary, 54th (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Anniversary, 55th (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Anniversary, 56th (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Anniversary, 57th (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Anniversary, 58th (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Anniversary, 60th (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Anniversary, 60th: Proclamations (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 3)
- Anniversary, 61st (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Anniversary, 64th (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Anniversary, 65th (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Anniversary, 66th (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Anniversary, 70th (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Anniversary, 71st (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Anniversary, 73rd (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Anniversary, 76th (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Anniversary, 77th, 2013 (Box Shared Tamiment 189, Folder 14)
- Anniversary, 81st, 2017 (Box Shared Tamiment 189, Folder 14)
- Anti-Nazi Propaganda (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Archived Websites, November 2008-ongoing; 5 websites in 5 archived websites. (Box Electronic Records)
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of alba-valb.org and albavolunteer.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  YouTube Channel was added to attempt to capture the videos embedded in the website. In 2023, YouTube URLs were changed to better capture the videos on the channel.
  Scope and Contents
  The Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) is dedicated to preserving and communicating the history and memory of those Americans who participated in the Spanish Civil War on the Republican side ("volunteers"). It is also successor to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. The website was first collected in 2008 and contained history of the war and the veterans organizations; dgitized documents, audio, images, and video related to the volunteers; a database of the volunteers with biographies; exhibit catalogs; online lesson plans for teaching about the Spanish Civil War; the San Francisco Monument; book reviews; events; ALBA in the news; George Watt Essay Contest; Teaching Institutes; and information about the ALBA collections at the Tamiment Library. Overtime, content on the website increased to include online resources of other institutions with Abraham Lincoln Brigade collections; a glossary; ALBA's Robeson in Spain comic book; publications on the Abraham Lincoln Brigade; fundraising efforts; ALBA/Puffin Award for Human Rights Activism; Human Rights Documentary Film Festival; obituaries; staff biographies; and the Susman lecture series. In early 2020, the website redesigned. Additional projects documented on the website include information on the Jarama Society; "Invisible Heroes: African Americans in the Spanish Civil War" documentary; the Perry Rosenstein Cultural Series; annual galas; and the Good Fight fundraising campaign.
  They also publish the quarterly journal, The Volunteer. Capture of the Volunteer's website began in 2010. The journal covers interviews, essays, obituaries, book reviews and other reviews, videos, research news, exhibitions, Tamiment Library updates, the Passport project and other database updates, speeches and presentations, the history of progressive activism, letters to the editor, current events interpreted through the lens of the Spanish Civil War, and other news related to the Spanish Civil War and the volunteers. Back issues of the Volunteer on the website date back to 1938.
  The YouTube Channel contains videos related to virtual events and galas put on by ALBA during the COVID-19 pandemic. Topics include the memorial for Judy Montell, fundraising videos, Question and Answer panels on books and films related to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, Memorial and Veterans Days tributes; Susman Lectures; other lectures; and monument commemorations.
- Archives: U.S. and Britain (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Archivo de las Brigadas Internacionales, Madrid (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Argentinean Volunteers (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Armenian-American Volunteers (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Artists (in Abraham Lincoln Brigade) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Attorney General's List (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Asian Volunteers (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Asociacin de Amigos de las Brigadas Internacionales (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Asociacin de Descendientes del Exilio Espanol (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Asociacion de Ex-Presos y Represaliados Politicos (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Australian Volunteers (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Austrian Volunteers (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Aviation: G. Hall Roosevelt (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Aviators: Condor Legion (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Aviators: General (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Aviators: Soviet (Paul Whelam File) (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Aviators: Spanish (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Aviators: US (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Bakery and Confectionery Workers, Local 87 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Banners and Flags (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Barcelona (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Battlefield Tourism (Nationalist): S. Holguin Article (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Belchite (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Belgian Volunteers (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Belgian Volunteers: Award to VALB (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 4)
- Benicassim (Hospital) (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Books: Spanish Civil War (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Botvin Committee to Aid Jewish Volunteers in Spain (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Botwin Company (see also Jews in the Spanish Civil War) (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Brandeis University: Spanish Civil War Collections (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Bremen: Nazi Flag Incident (Box 16, Folder 12)
- British Volunteers: 60th Anniversary/War Memorial (Box 16, Folder 13)
- British Volunteers: Ambulance Drivers (Box 16, Folder 14)
- British Volunteers: Archives (Box 16, Folder 15)
- British Volunteers: General (Box 16, Folder 16)
- British Volunteers: Hull, England (Box 16, Folder 17)
- British Volunteers: Individuals (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Brooklyn Volunteers (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Brookwood Labor College Graduates in the Spanish Civil War (Box 16, Folder 20)
- Browden Brigade (Box 16, Folder 21)
- Brownsville (Box 16, Folder 22)
- Brunete (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Bulgarian Volunteers (Box 17, Folder 2)
- California Volunteers (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Camp Wo-Chi-Ca (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Canadian Committee for a Democratic Spain, The (! Amnistia !) (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Canadian Participation: Aid (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Canadian Participation: Archives (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Canadian Participation: Myron Momryck Correspondence (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Canadian Volunteers (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Canadian Volunteers: Hungarians (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Canadian Volunteers: Jewish (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Canadian Volunteers: Ukrainians (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Carmen: Spanish Civil War Inspired Production (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Catalonia (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Catholic Church and the Spanish Civil War (Box 17, Folder 15-16)
- Catholic Church and the Spanish Civil War: Fr. Michael O'Flan... Catholics and the War in Spain" (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Catholic Church and the Spanish Civil War (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 5)
- Cemetery of Fuencarral (Madrid) (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Centre d'Estudis d'Historia Contempornia (Barcelona) (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Chicago Friends of the Lincoln Brigade (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Chicago Volunteers (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Children, Aid to (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Children: Exiles in the USSR (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Children's Drawings (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Children's Homes/Schools (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Chinese Participation (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Christian Advocate Coverage (Methodist Episcopal Church South) (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 6)
- City College Volunteers (Box 18, Folder 11)
- City College New York (CCNY)/Baruch College: Volunteers in Lincoln Battalion, Exhibit (Box 18, Folder 12)
- City College Volunteers-in-Spain Memorial Scholarship Committee (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Colorado Volunteers (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Columbia University (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Columbia University: Guide to Spanish Refugee Relief Organizations (Box 18, Folder 16)
- Columbia University Volunteers (Box 18, Folder 17)
- Comite Antifacista Espanol (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 18, Folder 18)
- Commissars (Box 18, Folder 19)
- Committee for a Democratic Spain (Box 18, Folder 20)
- Communist Party of Spain (PCE) (Box 18, Folder 21)
- Communist Party, USA: California, Aid to Spain (Box 18, Folder 22)
- Confederacion Nacional de Trabajo (CNT) (Box 18, Folder 23)
- Conference: 50th Anniversary (University of Southampton, 1986) (Box 18, Folder 24)
- Conference: 50th Anniversary Commemorative Week (Queens College, CUNY, 1986) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Conference: 70th Anniversary (Paris, 2006) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Conference: 70th Anniversary (University of Salamanca, 2006) (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Conference: "Americans in Spain, The International Brigade: R...lling the Story" (Chicago, 1999) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Conference: "Continuing History of the Spanish Civil War" (NYU, 2007) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Conference: "Documenting Displacement: Images of Spanish Civil War Refugees" (NYU, 2009) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Conference: France, January 1939 (Box Shared Tamiment 169, Folder 20)
- Conference: International Conference on the Spanish Civil War (Barcelona, 1979) (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Conference: Lausanne, Switzerland, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Conference: Madison, WI, December 2006 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Conference: Madrid 2006 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Conference: Smithsonian Institution, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Conference: "Spain 1936-1976" (Bethune College, York University) (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Conference: "The Spanish Civil War Fifty Years After" (Penn State University, 1986) (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Conference: "The Spanish Civil War, Thirty Years Later (Harvard-M.I.T., 1969) (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Conference: "War without Limits: Spain, 1936-39 and Beyond" (University of Bristol, U.K.), 2006 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Coordinating Committee to Lift the Spanish Embargo, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Croatian Participation, 2002-2007 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Cuban Volunteers, 1995, 2004-2011 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Currency, 1971, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Curriculum Projects, 1981, 1989, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Cypriot Volunteers, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Czechoslovak Volunteers, 2001, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Czechoslovak Volunteers - List of Names and Biographical Information, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  Scope and Content Note
  Compact disc of 641-page document in Czech from Czech Liberty Fighters Association Archives with names and biographical information for 2,329 volunteers.
- Czechoslovak Volunteers - List of Names (copy of document from Czech Liberty Fighters Association Archives) - Introduction through page 315, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Czechoslovak Volunteers - List of Names (copy of document from Czech Liberty Fighters Association Archives) - page 316-641, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Czechoslovak Volunteers - List of Names (copy of document from Czech Liberty Fighters Association Archives) - page 642-679 (index of names), 1975 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  Contents are not entirely in alphabetical order.
- Daily Worker Coverage (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Daily Worker Coverage (Oversize), 1966 (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 7, Box Shared Tamiment 184, Folder 3)
- Debs Battalion/Debs Column, 1937, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Department Store Workers' Union, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Deserters (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Dissertations and Research Papers (Lists), 1986, 2004-2005 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Ebro, Battle of, 1978, 1982, 2003, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 4, Box Shared Tamiment 175, Folder 14)
- El Salvador, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Executions, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Exhibits: "Antifascistas, British and Irish Volunteers in the Spanish Civil War" (IBMT) (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Exhibits: "Aura of the Cause", 1997-1998 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Exhibits: "Brigadistas and Refugees: Crossing Borders with Ca... Mexico Suitcase" (NYC, May 2009 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Exhibits: Delphic Studios, NYC, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Exhibits: "Dreams and Nightmares": Imperial War Museum, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Exhibits: "Facing Fascism: New York and the Spanish Civil War", 2007 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Exhibits: General, 1976-2007 (Box 13, Folder 13, Box Shared Tamiment 184, Folder 4)
- Exhibits: "Imagenes Recuperadas", 2003 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Exhibits: Italy, Spanish Civil War Exhibits, 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Exhibits: "Lincoln Brigade in Aragon" (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Exhibits: "No Jubilem la Memoria!" (Les Masies, Spain), 2003; TW_ALBA_VF_001_ER_1 (Box 13, Folder 17, Box Shared Tamiment 184, Folder 5)
- Exhibits: "No Pasarn" (Jerusalem), 2003 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Exhibits: "Posters from the Spanish Civil War" (NYU, 2008) (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Exhibits: "Posters of the Spanish Civil War" (NYC, 1991) (Box 14, Folder 2, Box Shared Tamiment 184, Folder 6)
- Exhibits: "Shouts from the Wall", 1996-1999 (Box 14, Folder 3-4, Box Shared Tamiment 184, Folder 7)
- Exhibits: "They Still Draw Pictures" (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Exhibits: University of California Berkeley, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Exhibits: "Voices of the Other America," Prospectus, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Exiles, 2000, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 8, Box Shared Tamiment 184)
- Exiles: France, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Exiles: France (Oversize) (Box Shared Tamiment 126, Folder 8)
- Federacio Nacional de Pioneros de Catalunya (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Fight against War and Fascism (periodical) (Box 14, Folder 9, Box Shared Tamiment 184)
- Figurine: El mes petit de tots (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Film: "American Commander in Spain", 1985-1989 (Box 14, Folder 11, Box Shared Tamiment 169, Folder 21)
- Film: "Canadienses, Los", 1976, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Film: "Chronicles of Hope: the International Brigades in Spain", 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Film: "Defenders of the Faith", 2011 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Film: "Extranjeros de se Mismos" (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Film: "Forever Activists", 1989-1992 (Box 15, Folder 5, Box Shared Tamiment 169, Folder 22)
- Film: "Good Fight": General, 1980-1984 (Box 15, Folder 6, Box Shared Tamiment 184, Folder 10)
- Film: "Good Fight": NEH Grant Application, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Film: "Good Fight": Proposal and Funding, 1978-1979 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Film: "Good Fight": Reviews, 1984-1985 (Box 15, Folder 9, Box Shared Tamiment 184, Folder 11-12)
- Film: "Heart of Spain", 1937 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Film: "In Search of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade", 1996 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Film: "Into the Fire", 2002, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Film: "Land and Freedom" (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Film: "Madrid before Hanita" (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Film: "Ninos de Russia" (Box 4, Folder 3)